<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notebooks on San Diego Data Knowledge Base</title>
    <link>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notebooks on San Diego Data Knowledge Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:21:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title> Crime Monthly Rhythm Maps</title>
      <link>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/crime-monthly-rhythm-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/crime-monthly-rhythm-maps/</guid>
      <description>This analysis will examine six years of data that was aggregated by SANDAG and processed by the San Diego Regional Data Library to visualize crime patterns on a weekly and hourly basis. The analysis uses 797,978 crime incidents. The data is published in CSV and shapefile form at the Library&amp;rsquo;s data repository
These heat maps, also know as rhythm maps, are square grids where each hour of the week is represented by a cell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> San Diego Police Calls For Service</title>
      <link>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/san-diego-police-calls-for-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 21:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/san-diego-police-calls-for-service/</guid>
      <description>Eric Busboom, 7 Nov 2017
In preparation for the SCALE and Open San Diego Crime ANalysis Presentation, I downloaded the data package for the presentation and started on the analysis a bit early.
The presentation will use the San Diego Police 2015 calls for service, but the data repository has 2016 and 2017 as well. The seperate files for each of the three years are converted into a data package on our repository, and I also created Metapack packages for the boundary files for beats, neighborhoods and districts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> American Community Survey Demonstration</title>
      <link>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/american-community-survey-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 22:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/american-community-survey-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to use Metapack with data from Census Reporter to analyze US Demographics. You will need to install at least these python packages, using pip:
pip install metapack pip install publicdata pip install seaborn pip install geopandas pip install pysal Finding Data In Census Reporter The first step is to visit Census Reporter and find the dataset you want to work on. Census Reporter is probably the best search interface for American Community Survey data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Metapack Access Example</title>
      <link>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/metapack-access-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 22:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kb.sandiegodata.org/notebooks/metapack-access-example/</guid>
      <description>Metatab is a system for documenting data set metadata, which the program metapack uses to create data packages. You can also us the metapack python module to access data packages from the web, which provides easy access to documentation and pandas data frames in Jupyter notebooks.
To start, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install metatab, which you should be able to do with:
 pip install metatab
 The system is under active development, so if there are problems, you can install the latest development versions of the important modules with the development requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>